<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on kubekub</title>
    <link>https://kubekub.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on kubekub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 11:50:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kubekub.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps platform in Kubernetes production</title>
      <link>https://kubekub.com/blog/2020/03/11/devops-platform-i-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 11:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubekub.com/blog/2020/03/11/devops-platform-i-gitlab/</guid>
      <description> References </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run OpenShift 4.x locally</title>
      <link>https://kubekub.com/blog/2019/08/31/openshift-4-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 16:30:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubekub.com/blog/2019/08/31/openshift-4-local/</guid>
      <description>After some finding and waiting, we can have a way of locally test OpenShift 4 in our local machines. Thanks to an update to the post in the great article about the differences between OpenShift and Kubernetes we discovered that there is a replacement for Minishift and the &amp;ldquo;oc cluster up&amp;rdquo; command, not working for OpenShift 4. The only ways to test OpenShift 4 was with an installation in the cloud or the OpenShift online testing version (only free for a month).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio on GKE, the managed service mesh on Google Cloud</title>
      <link>https://kubekub.com/blog/2019/07/22/managed-istio-on-gke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 10:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubekub.com/blog/2019/07/22/managed-istio-on-gke/</guid>
      <description>Istio is becoming one of the standards in the service mesh scenario. It is being developed and pushed by some of the giants of the industry like IBM, Google or RedHat and now version 1.0 is going to celebrate its first anniversary.
All major cloud providers are including a service mesh in their managed services, like AWS with it&amp;rsquo;s App Service Mesh, IBM with the managed Istio add-on or Google Cloud with Istio on GKE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes certificates, my path to obtain CKA and CKAD.</title>
      <link>https://kubekub.com/blog/2019/06/29/ckad-cka-certifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 11:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubekub.com/blog/2019/06/29/ckad-cka-certifications/</guid>
      <description>In the last week I passed both exams of the CNCF for Kubernetes, first the CKAD (Certified Kubernetes Application Developer) and finally the CKA (Certified Kubernetes Administrator).
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Kubernetes and OpenShift for the last 4 years, and I wanted to challenge my knowledge through the certifications.
The CKAD exam First I went for the CKAD, even I&amp;rsquo;m working in the last years very close to system administrators I still fill closer to the Development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure as code with Terraform and docker</title>
      <link>https://kubekub.com/blog/2015/08/22/terraform-aws-wso2-esb-docker-sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubekub.com/blog/2015/08/22/terraform-aws-wso2-esb-docker-sample/</guid>
      <description>One of the good practices in a data center or a cloud infrastructure is to manage the infrastructure as code. There are many different options in the market as CloudFormation, Heat, terraform, etc. to create and provision the infrastructure and code. On Internet we can find different comparisons for the tools:
 thoughtworks.com ypoonawala.wordpress.com www.terraform.io  CloudFormation and Heat are specific for AWS and OpenStack, and Terraform can be used for multiple cloud providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Docker registry for WSO2 images</title>
      <link>https://kubekub.com/blog/2015/08/10/wso2-in-docker-registry-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubekub.com/blog/2015/08/10/wso2-in-docker-registry-en/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Once we know how to create a Docker image, if we want to share this image with the team, or use it in different environments, it´s possible to export it to a tar file, or use the Dockerfile to build the image on each of the docker hosts where it will be used. Having to rebuild the image on the pc of each of the components of your team is not very practical.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>